hi everybody welcome back to the channel
today we are going to make Bailey's ice
cream using Bailey's flavored extra
thick cream from the store so if you
want to see what it turns out like stick
around
[Music]
so at Christmas time I bought some of
this from the supermarket and they had
like a pouring version and then the
extra thick version it was an offer as
you know Christmas was done they were
trying to clear the shelves so I thought
I'd pick some up and make some Bailey's
ice cream with it now looking at the
ingredients let me
show you what I'm looking at here
looking at the ingredients there's just
double cream sugar Bailey's Irish cream
liqueur
and then some emulsifiers and regulators
smells reasonably strong of Bailey's
it is very very thick as you'll see in a
minute so let's just get on and make it
so the first thing we're going to do is
get all our ingredients out ready as you
can see here this is the exact tubs that
I used the Bailey's cream if you want to
pause it here to look at the ingredients
again feel free if not what we're going
to do then is put our milk straight into
the pan and start to heat that up whilst
it's heating up because my milk powder
is really bad at dissolving in liquid if
you've seen my videos before you'll
understand what I mean what I've done is
I've added the sugar to the milk powder
giving it a really good mix make sure
that all the sugar and powder are
Incorporated together then I'm going to
add that into the milk and actually that
milk powder then just dissolves almost
instantly which is amazing
at that point we're going to spoon out
this super thick Bailey's flavored cream
straight into the milk
keep stirring it until it's all
completely emulsified and dissolved at
that point you're going to take it off
the heat put it in a container where
you're going to leave it to cool down
slightly before storing it in the fridge
for three to four hours
after it's completely chilled down
you're going to take it out in the
fridge and something to point out is
that there was a really thick layer on
top of this and that indicates one thing
and it's quite High butter fat in this
cream here higher than normal cream in
the UK anyway to boost the flavor I
decided to add in some Bailey's actually
this is just stores own Irish cream
liqueur it's much cheaper and it's
actually better but hey who am I to
judge pour that into your base give it
one Final Mix and then you're gonna put
it in your machine to churn my machine
took 12 minutes to churn this but as is
alcohol in it yours might take just a
little bit longer
once it's completely turned you're going
to take it out put it in your tub pop it
in a freezer to completely harden off
this took overnight for me
so we've got our ice cream at the
freezer because alcohol in it doesn't go
as hard as other ice creams might so
we're gonna get some scooped up see what
it looks like and see what it tastes
like
Scoops as easy as any ice cream would
with alcohol in it obviously there's an
amount of alcohol that you can safely
put in ice cream before it just won't
churn at all or it becomes So Soft that
you know it kind of drips off your so
spoon but that's different depending on
the alcohol content in whatever it is
you're using Bailey's I don't know what
it is it's pretty low in alcohol in the
teens somewhere
you can probably use
I'm going to say somewhere around a 75
mil per liter in a good mix if you want
to add more then you're going to have to
look at decreasing the sugars which is
going to change
your solid content of your ice cream so
it's a bit of a balance properly using
alcohol in ice cream
it smells like Bailey's which is great
or Irish cream liqueur but you know this
is I'm saying Bailey's because this is
Bailey's branded cream but Irish cream
liqueur will work exactly the same it's
the same thing it's just not a brand
so let's see what it tastes like
first things first
flavor is excellent
it's really good it's just enough Irish
cream liqueur or Bailey's flavor coming
through it's not overpowering it's not
too strong it's not too weak it's just
about right flavor level is really
really good
smooth ice cream but
it has that kind of it leaves that film
and leaves that film on the spoon on
your tongue it's that sticky kind of
fatty taste now some ice creams that you
buy out there will do this because
they're really high in fat content
but there is a distinct difference
between fat content and butter fat
that's where the problem lies if you
have high fat content you can still get
super creamy without this fatty drag on
your spoon in your tongue and that's by
making sure that the butterfly isn't too
late and you can do that in various
different ways but this cream being
a manufactured cream obviously has
a high butter fat percentage in it it
doesn't say anything about it on on the
ingredient
the backlist there's no reason they
would because they don't say that on
normal cream containers but
I would be careful using this
I would be careful using flavored creams
for something like ice cream because you
don't know what the makeup of it is
whereas if I go and buy double cream
in England that's what we call heavy
cream and things like that double cream
in England is 50 fat content heavy
the US is you know somewhere around the
35 to 40 and in different parts of the
world it's different as well but if I
just went to the store and bought normal
double cream heavy cream I wouldn't get
that bottle of butter fat even up to
probably 20 22 fat content I've done it
many many times before you don't
flavored creams
this is the first time I've used the
Bailey's one and it's produced that
fatty drag but I have had it before on
other things like clotted cream clotted
cream is going to go too far with it and
it will create this fatty drag but hey
it was a bit of an experiment the cream
wasn't offer I thought why the bloody
hell not let's just see what it's like
I'm still gonna eat this and I reckon
even with the high butterback content
it'd be really really good on something
like a brownie or a bit of cake
you know something warm just to help
break that flavor of the alcohol down a
little bit in your mouth but really nice
ice cream
if you want to give this drawing you've
got some of this flavored cream go ahead
if not use normal cream and then add in
your Baileys after like I said up to 75
mil of Baileys per liter is probably
where I'd start and then start adjusting
it from there otherwise thanks very much
for watching don't forget to like And
subscribe and we'll see you next time
[Music]
thank you